JOEY LAI

Software Generalist

• Calgary, AB
• 403.397.3556

☑ joey@jlai.ca

jlai.ca

github.com/jlai403

in linkedin.com/in/jlai403

Skills

Team & Agile Collaboration



SCRUM, Sprint focused, Agile, Lean, Pair programming, Iterative Development

Full Stack Developer



Node.js, C#, Java, Swift, AngularJS, Vue.js

T-SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, ORM

TDD, Refactoring, Systems Architecture, Design patterns, UX

ETL & Data Warehousing



Microsoft SSIS, Data/Dimensional modelling, Data cleansing, Data Analysis

HighCharts, Tableau, Plotly.js

Dev Ops



Continuous Integration & Deployment, Docker, New Relic

AWS, Windows Server, Ubuntu

References

Available upon request

Summary

Pragmatic software developer & lifelong learner. 7 years of experience developing products with highly collaborative and high functioning teams. Conforms to best development practices and not attached to any particular programming language/framework - decision should be made to best meet the requirements of the business. Constantly self improving skills leadership skills and learning new technologies

Professional Experience

Product Development & Data Architecture Lead

StellarAlgo Corp. (Duck Labs), 2017 - Present

Data-based SaaS platform positioned to help live audience organizations. An all around developer wearing multiple hats - SCRUM Master, ETL/Integrations Developer, Data Architect, Full Stack Developer, QA, Dev Ops/Sys Admin, Data Analyst

Software Development Consultant

Duck Labs, 2016 - Present

Part of the core development team, working with multiple clients varying from entrepreneurs to large enterprises as a Product Development Consultant.

Founder

jlai Consulting Inc., 2013 - Present

Software Developer

QuickEstate (Duck Labs), 2016 - 2017

Worked with a small group of talented team members to redesign and develop a SaaS based product to drive sales.

Software Developer

LiDAR Services International (Duck Labs), 2016

Assisted in the development of a GIS application for gas leak detection and mapping of pipelines.

Software Developer

Knelf, 2014 - 2016

Worked with highly skilled individuals with great visions and leadership in developing a social learning platform, providing tools for individuals to better themselves in a fun and engaging experience.

Production Support Developer

Evoco Inc. (ITForDev), 2013 - 2014

Implementation and integration of client services into a SaaS construction management system.

Junior Software Developer

CGI Group Inc., 2011 - 2013

Education

Bachelor of Computer Information Systems, Business Minor

Mount Royal University, 2012 - 2015

Cumulative GPA of 3.68 Deans Honor Roll

Diploma in Information Technology - Software Development

SAIT Polytechnic, 2009 - 2011

Cumulative GPA of 3.85 Graduated with Honors

Certifications/Honors/Awards

MRU Dean's Honor Roll, 2012/2013

SAIT Honor Roll, 2011

SAIT Information Systems Award, 2010

Acclivus R3 interAction Certificate (Rogers Sales Consultant), 2009

Acclivus R3 transAction Certificate (Rogers Sales Consultant), 2009

Rogers Sales Certification, 2008

Alex Rutherford Scholorship, 2009